Dungeons & Dragons: Wrath of the Dragon God is a action,
adventure, fantasy film directed by Gerry Lively.
Due to a curse from his former master Profion, Damodar survived his death by Ridley Freeborn as an undead entity in pursuit of an evil artifact for some
hundred years, so that he might be capable of unleashing unstoppable destruction on Izmir and the descendants of those who caused his demise.
Damodar, played by Bruce Payne.
Berek, played by Mark Dymond.
Melora, played by Clemency Burton-Hill.
Lux, played by Ellie Chidzey.
Nim, played by Tim Stern.
Dorian, played by Steven Elder.
Dungeons & Dragons: Wrath of the Dragon God is a 2005 direct-to-video American fantasy adventure
film directed by Gerry Lively and written by Brian Rudnick and Robert Kimmel.
The second instalment in the Dungeons & Dragons film series, it serves as a stand-alone sequel to
Dungeons & Dragons (2000), which in turn was based on role-playing game of the same name.
The only returning actor is Bruce Payne, reprising his role as Damodar.
The film premiered at the Sci-Fi Channel on October 10, 2005.
It was released in theaters in Europe as well as some parts of North America
and Latin America, and released on DVD on February 7, 2006.
Dungeons & Dragons: Wrath of the Dragon God was followed by Dungeons & Dragons 3: The Book of
Vile Darkness, released direct-to-DVD in the United Kingdom on August 9, 2012.
The film explores themes of fighter, royalty, curse, dragon, d&d.